Guide to the Jack Lambert papers, 1970-2012.
Lambert, Jack papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Jack Lambert papers, 1970-2012.
21-1-4172
Lambert, R. L.,(Jack)
2
Manuscripts, publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection contains artwork and items relating to his Cornell work as well as personal drawings.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Robert "Jack" Lambert graduated from Cornell in 1950 and returned to the University as an instructor in 1953. Starting in 1962 he led Cornell's freehand drawing program, becoming a full professor in 1977. His coursework, mainly in the Department of Floriculture and Ornamental Horticulture in the College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, taught freehand, nature, and scientific drawing, as well as watercolor painting.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection contains artwork and items relating to his Cornell work as well as personal drawings. Includes cartoons and drawings relating to campus projects, publications featuring Lambert's work, course material. Many large scrolls of drawings and watercolor that tell a story, some scrolls extend 30+ feet. Several art journal notebooks. A number of items feature the Lambert Pump Company.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Lambert, R. L., Jr.; Lambert, R. L., (Jack) Jr.; New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences. Department of Floriculture and Ornamental Horticulture.
Subjects:
Scientific illustration.; Freehand drawing.
Form and Genre Terms:
Watercolor (paint)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See also CALS Freehand Drawing Collection, #21-25-3736, http://resolver.library.cornell.edu/cgi-bin/EADresolver?id=RMA03736.
CONTAINER LIST
- Department and Campus Related Cartoons, 1970s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Scenic Watercolors, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Sketches and Drawings of Cornell Buildings, Scenes, Locations, 1990s (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Demonstrations Practice, 2011 and earlier (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Publications (many concerning Cornell) with Lambert´s Illustrations, 2000s (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Sketches and Artistic Tutorials (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Artist Drawing Pens (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Papers Mainly Related to Art and Lambert Pump Company (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Assorted Photographs, Mainly of People (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Handouts and Papers from Courses (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Awards and Recognition, 1995 onwards (Box 1, Folder 11)
- "Figure Notes" from Here and There (Box 1)
  Notebook with sketches focusing on the human figure
- "Watercolor", 1980s (Box 1)
  Notebook with watercolors and some sketches, mostly landscapes and buildings
- Untitled Art Journal, 2008-2009 (Box 1)
  Notebook with sketches mostly focusing on "form"
- "Figure Notes" from Here and There, 1970s-1990s (Box 1)
- Untitled, 1976 (Box 1)
  Scroll with panels of watercolor art, located at Lambert's Pump Company
- "The Sands of the Desert" (Box 1)
  Scroll with panels of watercolor art
- "Tree Grow- in Perspective" (Box 1)
  Scroll with panels of sketches
- "News-Likes of Yesteryear (Box 1)
  Scroll with panels of sketches "from the Lambert Pump Co. Archives of Fact and Fiction
- "Are You Tired of Studying?, 1982 (Box 1)
  Scroll with panels of sketches from "Lambert Pump Co." "in techna-color, watercolor, pencil color, penic color, and more..."
- "Tree Grow- in Perspective (Box 1)
- Untitled (Box 1)
  Scroll with panels of sketches, the first few depicting a morning routine
- "Hoshonuma, the Ancient Art" (Box 1)
  Scroll with panels of sketches focusing on Asian art
- "Private Eye - Jack, Case of the Vanishing Point" (Box 1)
  Scroll with panels of art
- "Making a Film-Like and Sketchbook Image", 1977 (Box 1)
- "La Naturaleza tiene dos caras", Fall 1983 (Box 1)
- Assorted Handmade Miniatures (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Lambert Pump Company "Gold" Watch (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Miniature of Family Gazing Upwards (Box 1, Folder 14)
- "The Penny Award - President and Chief R. Lambert" (Box 1, Folder 15)
- "Clouds of the Masters" Handmade Miniature (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Miniature Model of a Potted Plant (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Model of Desk with Art Posters (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Lambert Pump Company Artistic Papers (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Lambert Pump Company Artistic Papers (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Cornell Campus Drawings (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Watercolors, Drawings, and Other Artistic Renderings (Box 2)
  Includes still life works, natural landscapes, and buildings